All right, it's project time. So, what
we're going to create here is a number
guessesser. So, I want you to write a
program in JavaScript where the computer
tries to guess a number that the user
has in their head. Follow the steps
below to complete the assignment. You're
going to welcome the user with a
message. You're going to ask them to
provide you the top number in the range
and the bottom number in the range. Um,
then you want to display an alert to let
them know the game has started. And then
once you've done that, you want to have
the computer guess the middle number in
the current range. So, if they said, uh,
the current range is 1 to 100, then
you'd say, have the computer guess 50.
And then you're going to prompt the user
to see if the guess is correct. They
should respond with H if the guess is
too high, L if the guess is too low, or
C if the guess is correct. And then you
want to make sure to normalize your
input. So, if they give you a capital C,
then you still want to count that as a
lowercase C. Um, it's in one of the
previous videos, but if you need a hint,
check W3 schools. Then based on their
response, adjust your range accordingly.
So if you guessed 50 out of the range of
1 to 100 and they said too high, then
you automatically know that the number
is between 50 and one. So what you'll do
is you'll say, okay, the new range is
between 50 and one. So then you'll guess
25. And then as long as you keep
guessing the middle of the range, it'll
keep drastically reducing the amount of
possible answers. So, if it's too high,
the new maximum becomes whatever the
computer guessed last. If it's too low,
the new minimum becomes whatever the
computer guessed last. And then you'll
repeat the process um of guessing the
middle number and adjusting the range
until the computer gets the correct
number. Once it gets the correct number,
I want you to display the number of
attempts it took. And as usual, make
sure you have the correct comments
throughout your code um to make sure
that it's documented for future use.
Good luck.